Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Anarchism TAM.504
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Anarchism
2007-
TAM.504
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
0.0010 linear feet (1+ websites: i.e., a collection of websites that grows on an ongoing basis)
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Alternative Mass Media, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The Tamiment Library creates topically based archives of websites documenting labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States, with a particular focus on New York City. The collection contains periodically archived websites of entities that identify with / are inspired by anarchist ideas, with a concentration on contemporary anarchism, in particular New York based anarchism. Websites representing syndicalism, a related doctrine which advocates that governing power be invested in an association of labor unions, are found in the Library's Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) web archive. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Contents note
Contains periodically archived websites of entities that identify with / are inspired by anarchist ideas, with a concentration on contemporary anarchism, in particular New York City based anarchism. Anarchism (sometimes called Libertarianism) for the purposes of this archive, is understood as the ideal of a society composed of freely associating individuals, lacking a traditional state apparatus or other structures of domination that can compel obedience, and which share the Marxian advocacy of ending private ownership of the means of production. Syndicalism, which advocates that governing power be invested in an association of labor unions, is a related doctrine, although most syndicalist entities are found in the Library's Labor Unions and Organizations (U.S.) web archive. NOTE: For technical, privacy and other reasons, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. NOTE: if a link for an individual site does not work, click on the TITLE of the collection (in the "Description" section at the beginning of the finding aid) to access this web archive, then go to the site list and select the web site(s) you wish to view.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left): Anarchism, was created with the Web Archiving Service from the California Digital Library. This service employs open source web archiving utilities developed by Internet Archive with the support of the The International Internet Preservation Consortium. The Web Archiving Service was made possible with support from the National Digital Information and Infrastructure Preservation Program and the University of California, as part of a project to preserve born-digital political communication. The role of the Tamiment Library during this project and thereafter was/is to create topically based archives of websites documenting contemporary and ongoing labor and left activity, principally that based in the United States.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
A list of related Tamiment Library web archives, whose ns2:titles all begin with the prefix "Tamiment Library Web Archive (Labor and the Left), can be found at the website Web Archives from New York University Libraries
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Websites arranged alphabetically.
Anarchism |z New York (State) |z New York.; Anarchism |z United States.; Anarchism.; Anarchists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Anarchists |z United States.; Anarchists.; Syndicalism |z United States.; Syndicalism.
- Anarchism Web Archive, 2009-
  - 123 Community Space, 02/18/2009-07/11/2011
  - AK Press, 7/14/2011-
  - Anarcha, 09/21/2007-
  - Anarchism: A Bibliography of Internet Sites, 3/02/2011-
  - Anarchist Black Cross Federation, 09/21/2007-
  - Anarchist Encyclopedia Index, 2/22/2011-
  - Anarchist Jeopardy, 6/1/2011-
  - Anarchist Yellow Pages USA, 07/26/2009-
  - AnarchistNews.org, 1/13/2009-
  - Anarchy Archives: An Online Research Center on the History and Theory of Anarchism, 3/04/2011-
  - Bluestockings: Bookstore, Fair Trade Cafe, Activist Center, 07/26/2009-
  - Bureau of Public Secrets, 5/07/2008-
  - Chomsky, Noam, 5/07/2008-
  - CrimethInc. Ex-Workers Collective, 4/25/2012-
  - Freegan.Info, 07/26/2009-
  - Green Anarch, 5/07/2008-
  - llvox: Anarchist People of Color, Race, Anarchy, Revolution, 07/26/2009-
  - Institute for Anarchist Studies, 07/26/2009-
  - New York City Anarchist Bookfair Collective, 07/26/2009-
  - New York Metro Alliance of Anarchists, 9/21/2007-10/19/2009
  - Northeast Anarchist Network, 3/30/2011-
  - Northeastern Federation of Anarchist Communists, 07/28/2009-
  - Nothingness.org, 08/15/2009-
  - On Gogol Boulevard, 08/08/2009
  - R.A. Forum / Research on Anarchism, 08/19/2009-
  - Robert Graham's Anarchism Weblog, 6/6/2011-
  - The Situationist International Text Library, 7/16/2009-
  - Social Anarchism, 3/4/2011-
  - Strike Everywhere, 4/27/2012-
  - Utopian Mag, 7/27/2011-
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance, 04/19/2009-